Finding Aid for the Sylvia Brigham-Dimiziani Collection of Annotated and Manuscript Scores, 1921-1978
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Sylvia Brigham-Dimiziani Collection of Annotated and Manuscript Scores 1921-1978
Mus. Arc. 70
Brigham-Dimiziani, Sylvia
1 box (11 items)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
The Sylvia Brigham-Dimiziani Collection of Annotated and Manuscript Scores contains eleven musical scores including three works by Lukas Foss that contain markings entered on the scores by Sylvia Brigham-Dimiziani in preparation for performances.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Sylvia Brigham-Dimiziani, 2000.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Biographical Note
Sylvia Brigham-Dimiziani was born in 1937. She received her earliest musical training on the piano before studying voice. She earned her Bachelor's degree from Pomona College (1959) and her Master's degree from Juilliard School of Music (1961). She also studied in Paris at L'Ecole Normale de Musique as a Fulbright Scholar, at the Mozarteum in Salzburg, with a coach at Rome Opera, and at the Darmstadt Fereinkurse für neue Musik. She came to Buffalo in 1964 as a member of the first group of Creative Associates at the Center of the Creative and Performing Arts. After leaving Buffalo in 1966 she performed in Italy before joining the faculty at California State University, Northridge. She returned to Buffalo in 1970 to join the music faculty at the University at Buffalo. She remained on the faculty until her retirement in 2001.
While at the University at Buffalo Professor Brigham-Dimiziani taught voice lessons, vocal diction, and courses in vocal literature and chamber music. Her performances as a soprano covered a wide range of repertoire, including works by Bach, Handel, Bononcini, Mozart, Schumann, Satie, Roussel, Ravel, Arrigo, Ives, Schoenberg, Webern, Brant, Del Tredici, Foss, Rorem, Smit, Pousseur, and Fredric Myrow, who composed his Songs from the Japanese for her voice while they were both Creative Associates. Her career was international in scope, with performances at the Maggio Musicale in Florence, the Domaine Musical in Paris, with the Berlin Philharmonic, the New York Philharmonic, and Cleveland Orchestra.
Scope and Content Note
The Sylvia Brigham-Dimiziani Collection of Annotated and Manuscript Scores contains eleven musical scores including three works by Lukas Foss that contain markings entered on the scores by Sylvia Brigham-Dimiziani in preparation for performances. The other works are all for solo voice or voice and piano. They include two settings of poetry by Muriel Muschamp (Orr-Ewing).
Arrangement
The collection is in one series, arranged alphabetically by either composer or author of text, and then alphabetically by title.
Container List
- Angrave, Carl Mignonette: song 1921, 1 manuscript score (3 pages) (Box 1, Item 1)
  Ink manuscript. For voice and piano.
  Music by Carl Angrave with text by Muriel Muschamp [Muriel Orr-Ewing]. First line of text: A little bunch of mignonette.
- Carpenter, Edward, 1844-1929 The idler undated, 1 leaf of manuscript music (Box 1, Item 2)
  Pencil manuscript. Vocal line only.
  Text by Edward Carpenter, from his work, Towards democracy. Composer of music not identified. First line of text: I am he that beholds and praises the universe.
- Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009 [Thirteen ways of looking at a blackbird] 1978, 1 manuscript score (17 leaves) (Box 1, Item 3)
  Photocopy of manuscript. Leaves taped together for performance purposes and marked for performance throughout.
  For voice (soprano or mezzo-soprano, possibly tenor or high baritone), percussion (1 performer playing inside the piano on strings with tape covered triangle beaters, 2 cowbells, 2 bowls balancing on piano strings, and using a superball mallet, flexatron and Jew's harp), piano, and flute; with 2 tape recorders (optional).
  Text by Wallace Stevens.
  Accompanied by 3 December 1978 UB Percussion Ensemble concert program on which the work was performed.
- Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009 [Thirteen ways of looking at a blackbird] 1978, 1 manuscript score (17 leaves) (Box 1, Item 4)
  Photocopy of manuscript. Marked for performance throughout.
- Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009 Three airs for Frank O'Hara's angel 1972, 1 manuscript score (15 leaves) (Box 1, Item 5)
  Photocopy of manuscript. For male speaker, soprano solo, small women's chorus, 1 piano, 1 mandolin or guitar, and/or harp or harpsichord, 1 percussionist, and 1 tape recorder. Score bears small number of performance markings.
  Text by Frank O'Hara.
- Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009 Time cycle: four songs for soprano, clarinet, cello, percussion, and piano-celesta New York: Carl Fischer, 1964, 2 scores (Box 1, Item 6)
  Piano-full score and Soprano solo with piano reduction. Both scores marked for performance.
  Texts by W. H. Auden, A. E. Housman, Franz Kafka, and Friedrich Nietzsche.
  Accompanied by 226 February 1969 International Society for Contemporary Music concert program on which the work was performed and a Los Angeles Times 28 February 1969 review of the concert.
- Macky, A. M. Sister, awake: Old English lyrick undated, 1 manuscript score (2 pages) (Box 1, Item 7)
  Traditional English text set to music by A. M. Macky. First line of text: Sister, awake, close not your eyes.
- Mistral, Frédéric, 1830-1914 Magali undated, 1 manuscript score (1 leaf) (Box 1, Item 8)
  Text by Frédéric Mistral; traditional French tune set by unknown arranger. First line of text: O Magali, ma tant aimée.
- Orr-Ewing, Muriel M. (Muriel Muschamp), 1900-1994 You spoke of shells 1931, 1 manuscript score (2 pages) (Box 1, Item 9)
  Text by Muriel Muschamp (later Orr-Ewing) set by unidentified composer. First line of text: You spoke of shells for forgetting.
- Petzold, Alfons, 1882-1923 Mann weiss nicht wie man lebt in diesen Tagen undated, 1 manuscript score (4 pages) (Box 1, Item 10)
  Pencil manuscript. For voice and piano.
  Text from Alfons Petzold's Der Frühling from his Heimat Welt set by unidentified composer.
- Unknown U. N. A. undated, 1 manuscript score (2 pages) (Box 1, Item 11)
  No attributions for author of text or composer. First line of text: Standing together shoulder to shoulder fighting for freedom and peace on earth.
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Contributors
Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009; Orr-Ewing, Muriel M. (Muriel Muschamp), 1900-1994
Subjects
Music -- Manuscripts; Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009 -- Manuscripts
Genres
Scores
Associated Material
Related Resources in the University Archives
Muriel Orr-Ewing Papers, 1822-1994
MS 70
Correspondence, diaries, photograph albums of previous hit Muriel Orr next hit-Ewing (nicknamed "Meiko"). Collection includes records as founding president of the British Association of Women Executives and headmistress of the English girls finishing school, The Grove. Also includes personal correspondence with opera singer, Adèle Leigh, child author Berthe Grimault, and other notable writers and poets.